Guide to the Stanford University, Program in Human Biology, Honors Theses
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Program in Human Biology, honors theses
1979-2006
SC4-4102
Stanford University. Program in Human Biology.
23 Linear feet (335 volumes in 21 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Program in Human Biology.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was received in several accessions from the Program in Human Biology. Additional theses were received from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Information about Access
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Program in Human Biology.
Access Terms
Biology.; Student papers.
Collection Contents
- Theses, pre-1990
  - Abram, Steven R., Pain Sensitivity in the Human Cornea., 1981 (Box 1)
  - Ahern, Rena Lou, A Test of the Inversion of Intensity Hypothesis Controlling for the Effects of Birth Order and Obstetrical Medication., 1979 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Robert, The Utility of a Retrospective Clinical Database for Primary Lung Cancer Patients., 1987 (Box 4)
  - Aviado, Domingo, The identification of Acetylcholine as a Neurotransmitter in the Leach., 1981 (Box 1)
  - Awad, Roger Edward, A Comparison of Achieving Styles in Men and Women of Various Undergraduate Majors., 1981 (Box 1)
  - Badger, James Thomas, The In-Vitro Effect of Adreamycin, a Commonly used Anti-Tumor Agent, on Cultured Chick Embryo Heart Cells., 1981 (Box 1)
  - Baier,Carl A., Assessing the Role of the Inferior Olive in a Model System of Motor Learning., 1983 (Box 1)
  - Barbe, Susan, Use of Selective Antagonists in the Study of Ergonovine's Vasoconstrictor Activity in Rabbit Thoracic Aorta: No Evidence for Alpha-Adrenergic or Serotonin Receptors., 1983 (Box 1)
  - Bart, Dilys, The Identification of Epithelial Cells in Sweat Gland Cultures., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Becker, Mark, Analysis of Elderly Daycare Centers in Urban Taiwan: Examining the Needs of Taiwan's Elders., 1987 (Box 4)
  - Besbris, Ava M., Discontinuity Question Modes: A Study in Attribution Patterns and Schizophrenia., 1980 (Box 1)
  - Blumberg, Deborah, The Use of Monoclonal Antibodies as Probes for Factors Mediating Intial Events in Neuromuscular Synaptogensis., 1983 (Box 1)
  - Boren, Ashley E., The Composition and Successional Status of Forest Types in the Coast Range of Mendocino County, California., 1983 (Box 1)
  - Braun, Christian Lee, Improving Corporate Innovation., 1987 (Box 4)
  - Brockbank, Bradley Ross, Globalism in the Emerging Post-Industrial Paradigm., 1981 (Box 1)
  - Burke, Redmond Paul, Applications of Cranial Computed Tomography: Establishing an Anatomical Basis for the ASI-II Subsegmentation Program., 1980 (Box 1)
  - Butler, Elizabeth Marie, Demographic and Social Correlates of Parenting a Very Low Birthweight Infant., May 31, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Buxton, Janet A., The Children of Alcoholic Parents: Assessing and Meeting the Needs of A Stanford University Population., 1979 (Box 1)
  - Camargo, Carlos Jr., The Effect of Cessation and Resumption of Moderate Alcohol Intake on Serum High-density Lipoprotein Subfractions- A Controlled Study., 1983 (Box 1)
  - Carpenter, Sarah, The Effects of Running on the Development of Osteoarthritis., May 1985 (Box 1)
  - Coffey, Tom, Assessment of Direct and Indirect Measurement of Physical Activity., 1982 (Box 1)
  - Cool, Jonathan, An Assessment of Selected Issues in Population Program Policy: A Case Study of the Phillipines.., 1981 (Box 1)
  - Deisher, Theresa Ann, A Comparison of the Effects of the Hypothalmic and Spinal Temperature Manipulation on Metabolic Heat Production in the Rabbit., 1984 (Box 1)
  - Dennings, Robin M., Left Anterior Frontal Aphasia., 1987 (Box 4)
  - Dickinson, Robert A., A Management Plan for Implementing Privacy Safeguards in Medical Information Systems., May, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Doane, John Allen, Lymphocyte Stimulation by Adherent Cells of Varying Density., 1982 (Box 1)
  - Echeverria, Begona, "A Rose by Any Other Name Would Smell as Sweet..." even if the Origin of the Language is Unknown? An Exploration of Language Use in the Basque Country., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Edelson, Richard H., Preferential Adhesion in Organ Specific Tumor Cell Metastasis., 1982 (Box 1)
  - Engs, John, The Black Rhinoceros (Diceros bicornis) in Kenya: Status and Policy Implications., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Epner, Daniel E., An in Vitro Model for the Study of Acne., 1982 (Box 1)
  - Filvaroff, Ellen Hope; See-Tho Kaus, Gene Construct for Secretion of an HLA Antigen., June, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Folwer, Shelia Johnson, Weight Change in Stanford Women., 1981 (Box 1)
  - Foster, Jonathon, Coping Behavior of the Elderly: A Comparison of Depressed and Normal Population., 1984 (Box 1)
  - Francis, Brian Alan, Influence of Infant Squirrel Monkey Volcalizations on the Behavior and Physiology of the Mother., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Glass, Jeffrey Craig, Animal Models of Attachment on Repeated Separations of Infants from their Mothers., 1981 (Box 1)
  - Glick, Seth, Proglumide enhances haloperidol inhibition of apomorphine-induced sterotypy gut not crcling., May 15, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Green, Ronald, Ontogeny of Spatial Memory in the Rat., May, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Greenlee, Rebecca, Spontaneous Otoacoustic Emissions in Humans: An Investigation of Diurnal Variation., 1987 (Box 4)
  - Gullingsrud, Eugene O., The Role of the Habenula and Fasciculus Retroflexis in the Neural Control of Sleep and Hibernation., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Guteirrez, Yvonne Rosela, Maternal Deprivation Potentiates the Adrenocortical Response to ACTH in Preweanling Rats During the Stress Hyporesponsive Period., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Guyer, Peggy Elaine, A Brain Region Necessary for a Simple Form of Learning., 1982 (Box 1)
  - Harris, Victoria, Forecasting Trends in Freestanding Ambulatory Surgery Centers., 1987 (Box 4)
  - Hatsukami, Thomas, Behavorial Effects of Amphetamines on Rhesus Monkeys Shown Color Slides as Stimuli., 1978 (Box 1)
  - Hauer, Karen, Age-Related Changes in Maternal Speech to Infants, Preschoolers, and Adults., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Higgs, Kathryn, D., The Effects of Lactose on Intestinal Development: Implications for the Treatment of Diarrheal Disease in the Third World., 1986-1987 (Box 4)
  - Hogan, John E., Mental Illness as Seen in Fiction: An Alternative Perspective on the Diagnosis and Treatment of the Mentally Ill., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Holmes, David T., Formation of the Engram in a Model Learning System., 1981 (Box 2)
  - Howley, William E., Television Advertisements for Contraceptives: Place, Time and Manner Preferences., 1982 (Box 2)
  - Huang, Virginia S., Depression in the Elderly: Validation of a Geriatric Self-Rating Scales for Depression., 1981 (Box 2)
  - Ikeda, Robin M., Birth Control Information and Contraceptive Services at Stanford University-- A Survey., 1982 (Box 2)
  - Jeffries, Jennifer, Computer Phobia: Why Some People Fear Computers., 1982 (Box 2)
  - Jelliffe, Amy, The Importance of Early Experience for Sound Location in Barn Owls., 1981 (Box 2)
  - Jennings, Carol, An Examination of the Effecs of Gender on Perceptions of and Performance on a Robotic Arm., 1984 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Craig R., Health Care in Rural, Remote Alaska., May 15, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Judson, Stephen, Neuroanatomical Substrates for Involvement of the Red Nucleus in Learning., 1982 (Box 2)
  - Katz, Sue, The Effects of Early Malnutrition on the Behavioral and Physiological Response to a Conditioned Taste Aversion Task., 1982 (Box 2)
  - Kelsall, Brian L., The Role of the HLA-D Locus in Macrophage-T Cell Collaboration in the Induction of Lymphocyte Transformation in Response to Herpes Simplex Virus, Type I, Antigen., 1980 (Box 2)
  - Kelsall, David C., Studies of Hepatitis-B Antigen Production by a Hepatoma Cell Line and Hepatitis-B Antibody Production by a Hybridoma Cell Line., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Klein, Marisa, A Study of Heural and Behavioral Asymmenties in Fish., 1980 (Box 2)
  - Kline, Carolyn R., A Preliminary Examination of the Program in Human Biology at Stanford University., 1981 (Box 2)
  - Kozak, Kathryn, C., Physiological Effects of Strength Training in Older Men and Women., June, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Kruberg, Walter Gordon, The Hierarchy of Neural Systems Involved in Motor Control., 1982 (Box 2)
  - Kyncl, Marketa M. A., LSD Binding in Solubilized Bovine Frontal Cortex Membranes., 1983 (Box 2)
  - Leander, Stacy, A Study of the Relationship Between Body Image and General Well-Being in College Students., 1982 (Box 2)
  - Lee, Sandra S, A Culturally Sensitive Response to the Mental Health Care Needs of the Aging Asian Population., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Leland, Scott, Oppressive Development: Drought in the Sertao of Northeast Brazil., 1984 (Box 2)
  - Lerman, Joel, The effects of Buspirone on sleep in the Rat., 1986 (Box 5)
  - Leslie, Lisa, The 1982 California Medicaid Reform: The Effect on Accessibility and Quality of Health Care for the Poor., 1984 (Box 2)
  - Lieske, Carol, Pornography: Defining the Limits. [In two volumes], 1988 (Box 2)
  - Marticorena, Dorinda, The Impact of Differential Training Upon Performance on a Robotic Arm and Upon Attitudes Towards Robots., 1984 (Box 2)
  - Maurer, Toby A., The Evolution of an Epidemiologic Study in Childood Leukemia., 1981 (Box 2)
  - McCluskey, Therese, Father-Daughter Incest: Treatment and Intervention., 1981 (Box 2)
  - McDonlad, Craig Michael, The Effect of Weight Loss from Gastric Stapling on Self Concept of the Morbidly Obese., 1983 (Box 2)
  - McKenna, Michael John, Comparison of Human Alkaline Phophatase Osoenzymes: Strcutrual Evidence for Three Classes., 1979 (Box 2)
  - McKenna, Mikie, An Esoenzyme System. [Title page not included] (Box 2)
  - Meikle, Susan L., Liability and Compensation for vaccine Infuries: Legal History, the Present System, and a Proposal for Change., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Menlove, Lynelle, Mapping of Alport Syndrome-Like Hereditary Nephritis to the X Chromosome., 1984 (Box 2)
  - Merchant, Tom, The Osmoregulatory Behavior of Tigriopus Californicus, A Tidepool Copepod., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Mikules, Michele, The Effects of Early Entry into Daycare on Mother-Child Interaction., 1987 (Box 5)
  - Miller, Rick, The Effect of Low Dose Continuous Irradiation on the Survival of CHO cells In Vitro., 1984 (Box 3)
  - Modlinski, Monika, Investigation of the effect of Dese Dextran on the Thermal Sensitivity of HA-1 Chinese Hamster ovary Cells., 1982 (Box 3)
  - Moore, Linda Y., The Pulmonary Excretion Rate of Carbon Monoxide as an Index of Total Bilirubin Formation in Adult Wistar Rats with Common Bile Duct Ligation., 1983 (Box 3)
  - Morgenthaler, Jennifer, The Development of a Protocol to Measure Plasminogen Activator Inhibitor in Rat Testis Cells., 1984 (Box 3)
  - Murray, Jann L., The Differential Impact of Prenatal Care of the Incidence of Low Birth Weight Among Blacks and Whites in a Prepaid Health Care Plan., January 10, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Ott, Derek, CCK-8S Modulation of [3H] Dopamine Release from Synaptosomes of the Nucleus Accumbens., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Patterson, Robin, Teacher Attitudes Toward the Mainstreaming of Hearing Impaired Students., May 1985 (Box 3)
  - Pennypacker, Leslye C., The Effects of Intraventricular Administrtion of 6-OHDA on Behavior and Spatial Memory in Rats., 1980 (Box 3)
  - Perez, Michael J., The Juvenile Court School System: An Evaluative Study of Organizational Goals and Achievements., 1987 (Box 5)
  - Prystas, Elizabeth, Post-Operative Left Ventricular Dynamics., 1982 (Box 3)
  - Randall, Teri, An Autoradiographic Investigation of Circadian Changes in Regional Cerebral Glucose Metabolism., June 1985 (Box 3)
  - Randle, Yvonne, Weight Change in Freshman Women: A Descriptive Analysis., 1980 (Box 3)
  - Ray, Nigel, Induction and Inhibition of Lesions in Disease Lesion Mimic Mutants of Maize., March 1986 (Box 5)
  - Reagan, Robert Timothy, The Right-left Dimension in Art: A Review of the Literature and an Empirical Study., 1980 (Box 3)
  - Replogle, Robert E., Characterization of the Interleukin-2 Enhancer., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Rich, Edward J., Dominance Behavior and Steroid Hormones in Two Types of Squirrel Monkeys., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Rose, Harvey, The Potential and Economics of Conservation and Renewable Energy Sources., 1980 (Box 3)
  - Sandrock, Alfred W., Jr., Regulation of Rat Pineal Hydroxyindole-o-methyltransferase: Evidence for S-adenosylmethionine-mediated Glucocorticoid Control., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Schmalzried, Thomas P., Dimethyl Sulfoxide Induced Changes in the Morphology and Protein Synthesis and Secretion of Myoblasts and Fibroblasts., 1980 (Box 3)
  - Sewell, Bradford Hardwick, Policy Perspectives on the use of the U.S. Imported Food Monitoring Program to Encourage Changes in Pesticide Use in Developing Countries., 1985 (Box 5)
  - Shafir, Sharoni, Coral Reef Conservation: A Study of the Effects of Fishing on the Coral Reefs of Kenya., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Sharma, Nutan, Purification of the Subunits of Bovine Dopamine Beta-Hydroxylase., 1986 (Box 5)
  - Shrift, Michael, Power Spectral Analysis of the EEG During Hypnotic Age-Regression., 1984 (Box 3)
  - Simone, Eric Anthony, Accumulation of a Heparin Sulfate Proteoglycan in the Culture Medium of Mouse Mammary Epithelial Cells., 1985 (Box 5)
  - Smith, Garrett, Carcinogen Metabolism in Cultured Human Epithelial Tissue., 1985 (Box 3)
  - Soohoo, Lillian, Gestalt Processing in the Cognitive Development of Normal and Autistic Children: A Comparison of Spatial Problem-Solving Strategies., 1985 (Box 3)
  - Spiekerman, Cynthia, A Culturally Specific Nutrition Education Curriculum for Ghana: Strategies for Decreasing Malnutrition., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Stone, Jodi, Mosquito Control in Northeastern Illinois., 1980 (Box 3)
  - Straut, David, The Management of the Fisher (Martes Pennanti) in California., 1978 (Box 3)
  - Sumits, Tracey, Neurolopsychological Functioning and the Dexamethasone Suppression Test in Patients with Major Depressive Disorder., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Swanson, Brian, The Ponto-cerebellar Pathway: An Alternative Explanation for (KCl induced) cortical spreading Depression impairment of a simple mammilian adaptive reflex response., 1983 (Box 3)
  - Taylor, Lisa, A Theoretical Cost-Benefit Analysis of Memory Intervention Programs for the Elderly., 1981 (Box 3)
  - Thrupp, Lori Ann, Deforestation, Agricultural Development, and Cattle Expansion in Costa Rica: An Integrated Approach to Problems of Land-Use Transformation., 1980 (Box 3)
  - Tinklenberg, Karla J., DRA I and SCA I Restriction Fragment Length Polymorphisms Identified at the Human Tyrosine Hydroxylase Gene Locus., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Ulmer, Todd, Claims for Wrongful Life and Wrongful Birth: The Standard of Care of Physicians Engaged in Prenantal Diagnosis., 1982 (Box 3)
  - Vickers, Angela J., Phychologically Induced Stress and the Squirrel Monkey., 1982 (Box 3)
  - Wang, Chia-Lien, The Effects of a Hypogravity-induced Environment on Zea Mays Seedlings Under Various Treatments., 1986 (Box 5)
  - Wentz, Kim Renae, Impact of Logging Operations on the Forst Environment of Oaxaca, Mexico., 1981 (Box 3)
  - Wilmarth, Linda K2, The Effects of Monoclonal Anti-C5a and Pentosifylline on Polymorphonuclear Leukocyte Lysosomal Release., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Wu, John, Transcription Analysis of Cytochrome C Oxidase Subunit I in Normal Maize Mitrochondria., 1987 (Box 5)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-1991-005
  - Abrams, Robert, The Theatre of the Environment., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Backus, Mark, The Effects of Bupivacaine on the Contractility of Rabbit Urinary Bladder and Renal Pelvis Smooth Muscle in Vitro., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Berman, Sarah, Investigation and Analysis of the Incidence of Allergic Symptoms in Patients with Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Block, Stuart I., The Genetics of Alcoholism: Mechanisms, Markers and Cyclic Amp., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Campbell, Allyson M., Reduced Adhesion and Spreading to Laminin Are Associated With a Glyco-sylation Alteration of a Laminin Receptor., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Davis, Debra K., The Effects of Varied External pH on Red Blood Cell Membrane Shape., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Day, Charles S., Temporary Lesions of the Raphe Magnus Nucleus and the Pre-Optic Anterior Hypothalamus in Thermoregulation., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Dungan, Elizabeth, Gender Differences in Life Satisfaction Ratings., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Essenmacher, Kirk, The Effects of Exogenous LDL on Adult Bovine Articular Chondrocyte Cell Proliferation in Serum-Free Medium., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Haberland, Corinna Anke, EEG Analysis of Hibernation in Ground Squirrels., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Hokanson, T. Erik, Individual Decision Making: Exchanging Money for Life Risk., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Huchton, David Morgan, The Effects of Differing Lengths of Maternal Deprivation on the Infant Rat's Adrenocortical Response to Novelty, Saline Injection or ACTH Injection During the Stress Hyporesponsive Period., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Hughes, Flint, The Coupled Effects of Alien Grass Invasion and Fire in the Seasonal Submontane Ecosystem of Hawi'i Volcanoes National Park., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Hurd, Stacy, Qualitative and Quantitative Aspects of Day versus Night Sleep in Physicians: Relationship to Performance and Mood., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Keiler, Leslie Susan, Using a HyperCard Writing Program to Enhance Scientific Learning for Middle School Students., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Kerns, Kara Lynn, Cloning and Expression of Glycoprotein G of Herpes Simplex Virus Type 2 in a Mammalian Cell Line., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Lee, Margaret M., Pharmacology of Autorhythmic Neutrons In Doriopsilla Albopunctata., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Lu, Michael Chunchi, Comparative Politics of Health and Medical Care in Taiwan and China., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Martin, Anne Marie, The Effects of Maternal Deprivation on Adrenal Sensitivity to ACTH Administartion During the Stress Hyporesponsive Period in Infant Rat Pups., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Mody, Tara Marie, Influence of the Early Maternal separation on the Behavioral and Physiological Responses to the Social Isolation in Adolescent Squirrel Monkeys., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Nirmul, Camlesh, The Behavioral and Physiological Response to a Novel Environment of the Infant Squirrel Monkey in the Presence of Its Awake or Anesthetized Mother., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Paik, Lisa Marie, A Critical Assessment of Trekking in the Annapurna Region of Nepal., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Pham, Teresa, Long Term Effects of Maternal Deprivation on the Hypothalamic-Pituitary-Adrenal Axis Responsivity of Rat Pups., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Raskin, Damon Bradley, Ultradian Rhythms of Gneital Vasocongestion in Men., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Reinier, Kyndaron, Health Care in Poland: The Ideology and Reality of Universal, Free Health Care., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Rodriguez, Beverly, The Prevalence of Sexual Coercion among Males and Females of Diverse Ethnic Groups at Stanford University., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Saigal, Cristopher S., Frequencies of Alleles Detected by Xmn I Cleavages in the APO A1/APO C3/APO A4 Gene Complex in Seven Human Populations., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Schrieber, Jonathan, Cloning and Characterization of a Cyclic AMP Independent Carbon Starvation Promoter of E. coli., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Sincich, Lawrence, Reconsidering Dendritic Behavior: Biological Implications for Parallel Distributed Processing Models., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Srinivasan, Sri, Evaluation and Implications of Rape Reform Legislation., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Torres, Michele Angier, Discrepancy in Perception of Compliance Between Adolescent Cancer Patients and their Caregivers., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Tseng, Marilyn, Induced Physiological Tolerance to Lactose., 1990 (Box 1)
  - Winslow, Cornelia Beth, Effectiveness of a Video-Based Aerobic Dance Exercise Program in Promoting Long-Term Heath-Related Fitness., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Woodward, Sue Adams, Dispersal of Myrica faya by exotic birds in Hawai'i Volcanoes National Park., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Yoo, Jeannine D., Firing At the Top: A Profile of Executive Dismissal., 1989 (Box 1)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-1991-151
  - Austin, Susan Allison, The Econmics and Institutions of Water Trading in California., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Dickstein, Michael E., The Politics of Medicare Physician Payment Reform., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Fennerty, Rebecca, Purification and Genotypic-specific Kinetics of Glucose-6-Phosphate dehydrogenase in Colias Butterflies., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Flom, Sharon L., The Predominant Use of Allopathy over Ayurveda in Rehabilitation Programs for the Physically Disabled in India., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Gani, Paula, Social Support, Homelessness, and Reciprocity: The Public Places Survey., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Koontz, Stephanie L., The Politics of Regulating Life: An Analysis of Cultural Patterns in French and American Reproductive Policy., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Lang, Olivia, The Consequences of Postnatal Psychosocial Stress on Adrenocortical Activity and Behavior in Mother-Infant Squirrel Monkeys., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Lee, Jane A., Cardiovascular Disease Risk Factors and Attitudes Towards Prevention Among Korean American Elderly., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Lin, Ki-hon, Effects of a Serotonergic 5Ht-1a Antagonist on Activity Feedback to the Mouse Circadian Clock., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Loffredo, Anthony J., Cardiovascular Disease Risk Factors in Strength and Endurance Trained Athletes., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Mungai, Lynette, Psychosocial Dimensions of Recycling for Students in High Recycling and Low Recycling Residences at Stanford University., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Romero, Anthony Corral, Health Status of the Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers in Northern San Diego County., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Shah, Saurabh B., A Study of Male Attitudes Toward Family Planning in India., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Sims, Carrie Adelia, Rape Myth Acceptance as a Function of Living Environment., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Takahashi, Tracy, Protein Folding: An Essential Requirement for Active Protein Production., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Wang, Ernest E., An Examination of Male Body Image, Self-Esteem, and Eating Disorders in a Bodybuilding Population., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Wei, Patricia, The Tissue Distribution of Zinc Protoporphyrin in Neonatal Wistar Rats., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Wong, Joann M., A Comparison of Adaptive Styles in Pediatric and School Samples., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Woo, Cynthia Faye, The Influence of Chronic Psychosocial Stress on the Infant Squirrel Monkey's Response to Permament Maternal Separation., 1991 (Box 2)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-1993-058
  - Baird, Traci Lauren, Mexican Adolescent Sexuality: Implications for Research and Policy., February, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Barclay, Elizabeth, Barriers to the Education of Homeless Children., June, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Bass, Jason, Analysis of the Surface Remains Recovered from Panakon, an Archeological Fortress Site Near Athens, Greece., June, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Brewster, Annie, Cultural Conceptions of Reproduction and Motherhood Among Tibetan Women in Exile: A Western Woman's Interpretations and Analysis., March, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Cocilovo, Costanza, Skeletal Health in Younger Women., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Cole, Wesley E., Improving Emergency Physician Alterness: Evaluation of an Intervention., May, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Faulkner, Camille A., Phototoxic Effects of Tin and Zinc Protoporphyrins in Rat Liver Tissue., June, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Filson, Lara Elizabeth, Principles for Successful Community Research: Learning from Experience., May, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Giardini, Alyson M., 1991 British National Health Service Reforms: Politics and Health., September 1992 (Box 1)